Guide to the Library Staff Association, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Library Staff Association, Yale University Library, records
1953-2009
RU 186
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.02
(8 boxes)
The records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, financial statements, reports, and publications documenting the activities of the Library Staff Association (formerly Managerial and Professional Staff Association) at Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-F (YRG 32-F), Records of Yale University Library staff organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Managerial and Professional Staff Association became the Library Staff Association (LiSA) in 2003.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records include agendas, minutes, correspondence, financial statements, reports, and publications documenting the activities of the Managerial and Professional Staff Association (now Library Staff Association) at Yale University Library.
Library employees; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University. Library
- Records, circa 1953-1981; Accession 1982-A-055
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
  - Agenda, minutes, meetings and other related materials, 1953-1981 (Box 1)
  - Agenda, minutes, meetings and other related materials, 1953-1981 (Box 2)
  - Elections, 1977-1981 (Box 2)
  - Financial Records: check books and ledgers, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - PSA Notes, 1972-1977 (Box 2)
  - Material from other libraries, 1969-1974 (Box 3)
- Records of the Managerial and Professional Staff Association, 1991-1995; Accession 1996-A-004
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2030
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.
- Records, 1952-1972; Accession 19ND-A-139
  The materials are open for research.
  - Staff association, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Staff association stationary, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.L.A. SORT, staff association, round table miscellaneous information, 1952-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bills paid, 1965 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Christmas addresses, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constitution, staff association, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Staff association, related material, constitutions and bylaws, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Election results, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gifts, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Staff association handbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Staff association, library memorandums of interest to the staff, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Staff association, library scholarship fund, 1952-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting notices, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New members, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Staff association, proposed position classification plan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bank statements, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bank statements, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Paid bills, 1965 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Professional activities and education committee, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Staff association, proposed position classification plan, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Staff association parties, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Questionnaires, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Questionnaires, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Retirement, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Social committee, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sort information, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Staff association 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Staff association 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Staff association 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Staff association 1969-1970, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Staff association 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Staff association, general, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Staff news, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Suggestion box, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Staff association ballots (parts 1 and 2), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Minutes and treasurer's reports, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Staff association, constitution and bylaws, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - YUL, Staff association, record of checks and deposits, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - YUL Staff association, tea committee expenses, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - YUL, Staff association, minutes, memos, and reports, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Records of the chairman, 1994-2003; Accession 2004-A-076
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - M and PSA miscellaneous, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - M and PSA election, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Staff art exhibit, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New staff reception, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blood drive, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ice cream social, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Canned food drive, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nooks and crannies tours, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Library holiday party, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Library holiday raffle, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Orbis 2 fest, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nooks and crannies, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Election, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New staff, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - M and PSA new member reception reports, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - M and PSA new staff reception, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - M and PSA, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Annual reports, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - M and PSA election, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - M and PSA statement of goals, SCOPA, M and PSA, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - M and PSA, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - YUL stationary, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - M and PSA election, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - M and PSA election, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - M and PSA blood drive coordination, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Holiday part and raffle, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - New staff and reception, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - M and PSA holiday raffle, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - M and PSA, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - M and PSA, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - M and PSA, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - M and PSA, Weaver and Conway, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - M and PSA, Glover and Weaver, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - M and PSA, special interest groups, Glover, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - M and PSA, Fenton and Nixon, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - M and PSA, microcomputer tours, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - M and PSA, invitations, new member reception, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - M and PSA, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Records of Stephen E. Cohen as chairman of the Library Staff Association, 2003-2004; Accession 2005-A-003
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
  - LiSA (Library Staff Association), 2003-2004; 38
  - MPSA (M&P Staff Association), 2003-2004; 13
- Annual report, 2007-2008; Accession 2009-A-125
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2044.
  - Annual report, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
- Records, 1992-2009; Accession 2011-A-021
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2045
  - Committee chair notebook, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder system_indicator_300373cdb7e552beb8bc97231e8bc952)
  - M+PSA Holiday party and raffle (folder also appears to include unrelated documents), 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - M+PSA Holiday party and raffle, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Unlabeled folder, materials from, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - M+PSA Holiday party and raffle, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Library holiday party, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - YUL-M&PSA Holiday party, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - LiSA: blood drive, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - YUL - MPSA, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Library Staff Association, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - LISA Holiday party, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Field Day, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Merchant letters, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Unnamed folder, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - LiSA, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Unsorted papers, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - LiSA committee agendas and notes, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Holiday party, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Unsorted, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - LiSA, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 19)